Ryan Williams

Software Engineer

RyanMichaelWilliams@gmail.com | RyanWilliams.io

Summary

I'm an end-to-end Software Engineer with industry experience in E-commerce and Marketing companies, specializing in Microsoft technologies using Windows Azure. I work on Continuous Deployment, API development and testing. I have worked in startup, mid-size and international corporate organizations in both contract and full-time roles. I enjoy working on projects that make an impact in the world, with a motivated team or independently.

Recent Experience

Senior Software Engineer at Link Launcher (Remote) - linklauncher.com

November 2016 - Present

Remote contract to design and develop white-label affiliate marketing network which runs in Windows Azure. The platform uses Stripe and Azure services with C# in ASP.NET. Continuous deployment scripts using Jenkins and Git check-ins were created. Additionally, work was done on advertisers' sites for API integrations, network pixel loading and page designs.

Lead Software Engineer at Rakuten (San Mateo, CA) - rakuten.com

January 2013 – October 2016

Worked full-time with Windows Azure, C#, ASP.NET (MVC), Entity Framework, PowerShell, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Git, TeamCity, Bamboo, AWS, Oracle and SQL Azure to deliver high availability, cloud-based REST APIs. Developed APIs for desktop and mobile clients in an Agile environment. Created unit, integration and performance tests. Developed task driven continuous integration and continuous deployment scripts used to release applications. Worked in FinTech space with large payment processors. Assisted with Bitcoin integration in Japan and the USA with travel. Contributed to open source on GitHub projects, attended industry conferences, hackathons and investor meetings for investment due diligence.

Technical Lead Developer at LyntonWeb (Remote) - lyntonweb.com

January 2012 - August 2012

Contracted to lead a team that built an intranet site for content ranking and employee evaluation. Client was large, Swiss company. Technologies included: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TeamCity, Mercurial, Fluent Nhibernate, ASP.NET, SQL Server 2008, AWS and C#. Internationalized application to accommodate several languages and countries.

Software Engineer at Jar Media (San Francisco, CA) - <u>jarmedia.com</u>

June 2009 - September 2011

Primary full-time developer at affiliate marketing start-up. Met with business owners and affiliate partners to create a high traffic, custom CMS pages that worked for several custom credit card processor integrations. Processed hundreds of thousands of credit cards, interfaced with CRM systems that did re-billing securely. Worked on optimizing, scaling and designing pages used by super affiliates. Technologies included: ASP.NET, C#, SQL Server, Windows Server, AWS, Cisco Firewall and external load testing frameworks.

Web Developer at Pioneer Technology Group (Orlando, FL) - ptghome.com

August 2008 - February 2009

Full-time web developer for Florida based government software company. Built a web portal in ASP.NET using Visual Basic and SQL Server for the real estate industry which managed digitized title documents for home owners. Additionally, worked on releases for county governments which manage state tourist tax revenue.

Education

- BSBA, Management of Information Systems University of Central Florida 2007
- BSBA, Marketing University of Central Florida 2007